Holding chopsticks is a little bit like holding a pencil, except that you have two of them and you move them together in a pincer movement. Most of them are made out of wood. They're also made out of plastic, bamboo, jade, gold, silver and even ivory, though I think that's not so cool anymore. Chopsticks are really well designed for eating small bits of food. They're good for picking up noodles. If you're skilled, you can eat rice, pick up dumplings, pieces of meat. There are some no-nos with chopsticks. You should not use the chopsticks like drumsticks, which I know is tempting. You don't want to stick chopsticks into a bowl of rice face-up. And the reason for that is it actually looks like a bowl of incense, so it sort of echoes death. Chopsticks are used in a huge portion of the world, across much of Asia, about 1.5 billion people are covered in the chopsticks sphere. Different cultures have slightly different variations of chopsticks. Chinese chopsticks will tend to be long and round, Korean chopsticks are flatter and often made of metal and Japanese chopsticks tend to be round and very, very pointy. While chopsticks are actually really commonplace in American society today, there was definitely a time in the late 1800s where this idea that Asian men, because they ate rice with sticks, were of a different quality than American men, who ate proper meat with a knife and fork. But when China and the United States began their diplomatic engagement in the 1970s, Richard Nixon, Henry Kissinger, had to practice eating with chopsticks. What's been really interesting to see is that as Asian cuisine has moved from the East into the West,
Sostener los palillos es un poco como sostener un lápiz, excepto que hay dos palillos y se los mueve juntos en un movimiento de pinza. La mayoría son de madera. También los hay de plástico, bambú, jade, oro, plata e incluso marfil, aunque creo que eso ya no es tan genial. Los palillos están muy bien diseñados para comer pequeños trozos. Son buenos para recoger fideos. Si eres hábil, puedes comer arroz, bolas de masa, trozos de carne. Pero hay cosas que no se debe hacer con los palillos. No se debe usar los palillos para tocar la batería, y sé que es tentador. No se debe poner los palillos en un tazón verticalmente. Porque, en realidad, eso se asemeja a la forma un cuenco de incienso, y eso recuerda a la muerte. Se usan palillos en gran parte del mundo, en gran parte de Asia. Unos 1500 millones de personas usan palillos. Distintas culturas tienen variaciones levemente diferentes de los palillos. Lo palillos chinos suelen ser largos y redondos, Los palillos coreanos son más planos y a menudo están hechos de metal, y los palillos japoneses suelen ser redondos y muy, muy puntiagudos. Si bien los palillos son realmente muy comunes en la sociedad estadounidense de hoy, definitivamente hubo una época a finales del 1800 donde estaba la idea de que los hombres asiáticos, dado que comían arroz con palillos, eran de diferente calidad que los hombres estadounidenses que comían carne con cuchillo y tenedor. Pero cuando China y EE.UU. comenzaron su compromiso diplomático en la década de 1970, Richard Nixon y Henry Kissinger tuvieron que practicar comer con palillos. Es muy interesante ver que, conforme la cocina asiática pasó de Oriente a Occidente,
chopsticks have become part of the experience. There's evidence of chopsticks as long ago as the Shang dynasty, which is about 3000 years ago, and they loved tripods during the Shang dynasty. So when you cook with these big tripods, chopsticks were actually really useful, because it was a way for you to stir and to reach without getting burned as the water was boiling in these really big pots. Chinese culture has knives and has forks. It uses them in many cases for cooking. But in terms of like what moved into the dining room, it was the chopsticks. One of the things about Asian cooking is that it often comes in very small pieces. And I think part of that has to do with the fact that it's actually a lot more energy-efficient to cook little pieces quickly. But also, then you don't have to cut them. So you have a circular influence, where the type of food that is cooked allows people to use chopsticks, and then the fact that you have chopsticks influences the food that you can cook. But at the same time, chopsticks reflect the communal nature of eating food. You'll have these dishes that you put in the middle, it's very family style. You go in with your chopsticks, and you put it on your rice, and then you eat individually. There's actually a famous sort of legend where everyone has these really, really long chopsticks, like way too long for them to feed themselves. And so in hell, everyone starves, because they can't pick up food and put it in their mouths. But in heaven, people take the same chopsticks and then feed each other.
los palillos se han vuelto parte de la experiencia. Hay evidencia de palillos desde la dinastía Shang, que tiene unos 3000 años. Durante la dinastía Shang les encantaban los trípodes. Y si cocinabas con estos grandes trípodes, los palillos eran realmente útiles, porque era una forma de revolver y alcanzar sin quemarse mientras el agua estaba hirviendo en estas ollas tan grandes. La cultura china tiene cuchillos y tenedores. Se los usa en muchos casos para cocinar. Pero al comedor llegaron los palillos. Una de las cosas de la cocina asiática es que a menudo viene en piezas muy pequeñas. Pienso que parte de eso tiene que ver con el hecho de que es mucho más eficiente en términos de energía cocinar trozos pequeños rápidamente. Pero tampoco es necesario cortarlos. Entonces hay una influencia circular, donde el tipo de comida que se cocina permite usar palillos, y luego el tener palillos influye en la comida que puedes cocinar. Y al mismo tiempo, los palillos reflejan la naturaleza comunitaria de comer. Los platos se colocan en el centro, implica comer en familia. Uno toma los palillos, los coloca en el arroz, y luego come solo. Hay una famosa leyenda en la que todos tienen palillos muy, muy largos, tan largos que no podían alimentarse solos. Por eso en el infierno todos morían de hambre, porque no lograban recoger la comida y colocarla en la boca. Y en el cielo, las personas tomaban los mismos palillos y se alimentaban unos a otros.